Finding Aid for the William Alford Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
William Alford Collection
1923-1932
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0762
.42 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
William Cutter Alford was born October 31, 1901 and graduated from the Vanderbilt School of Engineering in 1925. He was a member of the Kappa Alpha fraternity, a Commodore Representative in his Junior and Senior year, a member of the Y.M.C.A. cabinet of 1921, a member of the Owl Club in 1923, a member of the Vanderbilt Tech Club, and a Vanderbilt Glee Club member from 1921 to 1925. The Vanderbilt Glee Club was founded in February 1891and was one of the university’s first and most active student organizations. Mr. Alford later became a landscape architect, published poet and was a member of the American Association of Landscape Architects, the Torch Club, and Cheekwood Botanical Garden and Museum of Art. He passed away on October 27, 1982.
Scope and Content Note
The William Alford Collection dates from1923 to1932 and includes correspondence, newspaper clippings, programs and sheet music, a scrapbook and Vanderbilt Glee Club key. The programs list members of the Vanderbilt Glee Club for the 1922-1923 season. The scrapbook contains original photographs and paper memorabilia from Mr. Alford’s time in the Vanderbilt Glee Club. This collection documents Mr. Alford’s association with the Vanderbilt Glee Club and his time as a student of Vanderbilt University.
- Correspondence
  - to Chancellor Kirkland from D.W. Hollingsworth, March 4, 1924 (Folder 1)
- Telegram
  - February 1924 unsigned (Folder 2)
- Programs
  - Vanderbilt Glee Club Thirty-third Annual Concert Tour, 1922-1923 season (Folder 3)
- Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert
  - Times, February 23, 1924 (Folder 4)
  - Muscle Shoals News, February 24, 1924
  - Times, February 25, 1924
- Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert
  - Times, February 26, 1924 (Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert
  - Times, February 29, 1924 (Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert
  - Times, March 1, 1924 (Folder 7)
  - Nashville Tennessean, March 2, 1924
  - Florence News, March 2, 1924
- Newspaper Clippings – Former Vanderbilt Glee Club Members
  - May 2, 1932 (Folder 8)
- Newspaper Clippings – Undated Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert and Former Glee Club Members
  - Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert – Tri-Cities Daily, February 28, 1924 (Folder 9)
  - Advertisement Vanderbilt Glee Club Concert, February 29, 1924
  - Former Vanderbilt Glee Club members - Tennessean, April 1932
- Sheet Music – “Sleepy Baby” Signed by Vanderbilt Glee Club Members
  - Vanderbilt Glee Club Thirty-Fourth Annual Concert Tour, 1924-1925 (Folder 10)
- Scrapbook
  - Vanderbilt Glee Club Key (Folder 11)